Records of the Education Sector
World Bank Group Archives
- Budget management, 1997 - 2001, 2004; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-05; 3.78 linear feet of textual records
  * See Records of the Education sector - Education Sector Board records ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-04](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/education-sector-board-records)) for other records related to the sector board's involvement in budget activities.
  * See Records of the Education sector - Director and Front Office records ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-01](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/director-and-front-office-records-1)) for related records regarding the sector work plan and strategy.
  * See Records of the Education sector - Grant and trust fund management ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-06](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/grant-and-trust-fund-management)) for records related to the sector's administration and monitoring of Development Grant Facility trust funds supporting global programs and initiatives.
  * See Financial Policy, Planning, and Budgeting ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_110](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/financial-policy-planning-and-budgeting)) for records regarding Bank-wide programming and budgeting activities including budget policy development and planning.
  Records are subject to the World Bank Access to Information Policy.
  - Human Development Network Business Plan - Fiscal Year [FY] 1998 - 2000, 1997-03-29 - 1997-04-07; 30037842
  - Mid - Terms Review - Fiscal Year [FY] 1999, 1999-01-12 - 1999-02-18; 30037841
  - Business Plan Exercises - Fiscal Year [FY] 1999, 1997-06-30 - 1998-05-22; 30037840
  - Retrospective Review Fiscal Year [FY] 1999 - Business Plan Fiscal Year [FY] 2000, 1999-07-29 - 1999-09-16; 30037839
  - Human Development Network Education [HDNED] - Mid - Term Review - Fiscal Year [FY] 2000, 1999-12-08 - 2000-03-16; 30037838
  - Mid - Year Review of Work Programs and Spending of Anchor - Fiscal Year [FY] 1999, 1999-02-01; 30037836
  - Retrospective Review Fiscal Year [FY] 1998 - Proposed Program - Fiscal Year [FY] 1999, 1998-05-22; 30037835
  - FY99 - Retrospective Review / FY00 Business Plan - August 1999 - Correspondence 2, 1999-06-01 - 1999-07-01; 01676932
  - FY99 - Retrospective Review / FY00 Business Plan - August 1999 - Correspondence 1, 1999-06-01 - 1999-07-31; 01676931
  - FY99 Retrospective Review / FY00 Business Plan - June 1999 - Correspondence, 1999-05-01 - 1999-12-01; 01676872
  - Mid-Term Review - Correspondence, 1999-01-01 - 1999-03-03; 01676850
  - 1998 Mid-Term Review / 1998 Retrospective Review / 1999 Proposed Budget Plan - Correspondence, 1998-05-01 - 1998-12-31; 01676848
  - 1998 - 2000 - Business Plans - HDN - Correspondence, 1997-04-01 - 1997-05-01; 01676847
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Fiscal Year [FY] 2001 Work Program and Fiscal Year [FY] 2000 Retrospective Review - August 2000, 2000-07-10 - 2000-07-17; 30123590
  - Global Programs and Partnerships - 2004, 2004-03-24 - 2004-10-15; 30123589
  - Fiscal Year [FY] 2005 - 2007 - Business Plan - Background Documents - Ruth Kagia - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED], 2004-01-23 - 2004-04-09; 30123585
- Education Sector Board records, 1995 - 2006; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-04; 12.28 linear feet of textual records
  Series consists of various records maintained by the Education Sector Board of the Human Development Network (HDN) that was launched in September 1996. The Education Sector Board was one of the first sector boards to operate ahead of the Bank-wide reorganization in July 1997 that created networks to link staff working in the same sectors throughout the Bank.
  The sector board was chaired by the sector director of the Human Development Network Education Team (HDNED). Maris O'Rourke was the first to serve in this position (1996 - 2000), followed by Director Ruth Kagia (tenure 2001 - 2008). The board was comprised of staff drawn from the network as well as representatives from the regions, Development Economics Department (DEC), International Finance Corporation (IFC), and World Bank Institute (WBI) and was managed by a sector manager. Accountable to the HDN Council led by the Human Development Network Vice Presidency, the board was supported by a secretariat. Records in the series reflect the responsibilitiesof the board in setting the strategy for the Bank's work in the sector, endorsing business plans and budget, ensuring the regions and anchor perspectives were coordinated, overseeing the outreach and partnerships for the sector, and vetting grant and trust fund proposals for quality, consistency, and prioritization with sector objectives.
  A large portion of the series consists of meeting records including minutes, agenda, and reports from 1996 to 2006. There are records for one 1996 meeting held in December and a gap in the meeting records exists between 2004 and 2005. Some of the minutes contain handwritten annotations. Occasionally minutes are filed with copies of correspondence to the Office of the President or HDN Council, conference invitations and agenda, course outlines, draft and final discussion papers, external reports or newsletters, and other items. The minutes reflect discussion and decisions taken on various initiatives and topics such as: special grant proposals; preparation of reports or sector strategy; data and trends presented by sector staff including decline in education lending; external conferences and other events held by partners; quality assurance; Human Development Week event activities; fiscal year business plan and budget; staff training and development; awards programs; Bank reorganization; and various internal administrative matters. The minutes also specify follow-up actions to be taken.
  The series also consists of chronological files of the sector board (1995 - 2000, with agap between mid-1998 and 1999), sector manager chronological file (2001 - 2002), and several correspondence and external correspondence files in liaison with the Office of the President (EXC, 2002 - 2005), specifically Wolfensohn (1996 - 1998), executive directors (1996 - 1997), HD Council (1996 - 1997), and the network's predecessor, Human Development Department (HDD) front office (1996 - 1997). The EXC correspondence files contain the incoming correspondence and log sheet with instructions, the response prepared by HDNED director or staff on behalf of the director, and emails between staff regarding draft responses that were sometimes jointly drafted with the input of other Bank units.
  Subject files maintained by the sector board (1995 - 1999) also comprise the series. Files contain internal memoranda, external correspondence, and other records that relate to strategy, budget, funding, personnel, knowledge management, communications for the 1997 Human Development Network launch, Evaluation Learning Group, partnerships with external organizations, Development Grant Facility (DGF), and specific sector topics such as distance education and technology. There are also files related to the HDN Council that contain minutes of the HD Council meetings attended by O'Rourke and correspondence outlining directives from the HDD VP for the action of the sector board and regarding the launch of the networks including staffing matters. Correspondence is primarily between O'Rourke and other education sector senior staff such as Jeffrey Waite and Nick Burnett and includes all-in-1 messages and email hard copies, internal memoranda, and facsimiles. The correspondence is occasionally filed with internal reports such as working group and portfolio performance review reports, strategy papers, Terms of Reference, handwritten notes, and various other records.
  An additional set of records relate to sector strategy, quality, governance, and partnerships (2000 - 2003). Strategy files contain draft business plans, Terms of Reference,issues notes, sector board minutes, framework or working papers, concept note reports, guidelines, executive summaries, and other reports. Strategic areas include Education for All Fast Track Initiative (EFA-FTI), HIV/AIDS, user fees in primary education, adult basic education, early child development, science and technology, and other themes.
  Quality review records maintained by the sector board relate to the Quality Enhancement Review (QER) process for Bank-financed education projects at entry, quality training, and portfolio monitoring. The QER was initiated by the sector board in fiscal year 1999 and organized by the Quality Promotion Team, HDNED, in close collaboration with the Quality Assurance Group (QAG) and the regions. The purpose of the QER was to provide professional advice for country and task teams to enhance the quality and impact of projects and economic sector work (ESW). The files titled "Quality" contain: QER guidelines and overview documents; list of QERs FY2001 to 2003; QER panel roster; Terms of Reference; reports; and email hard copies regarding requests for QER by task team leaders (TTLs) and provision of quality training courses in collaboration between HDNED and Human Development Network, Health, Nutrition and Population Team (HDNHE) and HDNVP. The records pertaining to portfolio monitoring include quarterly reports, FY2002 retrospective report, and email hard copies between HDNED staff Omporn Regel and HDN Operations Officer Hongu Yang from HDNHE Lead Specialist Christopher Walker. Also included are four QER files related to Water and Sanitation and two related to Environment Sector Board QER that were presumably kept as reference.
  Records are arranged chronological or by subject.
  Records were transferred to the Archives by the Education Team, Human Development Network (HDNED) in 2001 and 2011 according to approved records retention schedules.
  No further accruals expected.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Director and Front Office records ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-01](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/director-and-front-office-records-1)) for chronological correspondence of sector directors and other records regarding management and oversight of the sector's programs, partnerships, strategy, and policy work.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Budget management ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-05](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/budget-management)) for related records of fiscal year business planning and reviews.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Partnerships and program collaboration ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-02](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/partnerships-and-program-collaboration)) for more records related to the sector's partnerships with external organizations and collaborative programs.
  * See Records of the Education Sector - Operational support ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-08](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/operational-support-2)) and Records of the Education Sector ? Knowledge management products ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-09](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/knowledge-management-products)) for Quality Enhancement Review records.
  * See Records of the Human Development Network ([WB IBRD/IDA HRD](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-human-development-network)) for HDN vice president correspondence and HDNVP unit chronological files.
  - Education Sector Board Fiscal Year [FY] 2003 Meetings - July - December 2003 - Volume 1, 2000-07-01 - 2003-10-09; 30123570
  - Education Sector Board Fiscal Year [FY] 2003 Meetings - July - December 2003 - Volume 2, 2003-09-17 - 2003-11-21; 30123571
  - Education Sector Board Fiscal Year [FY] 2003 Meetings - July - December 2003 - Education Sector Human Development Network, 2000-07-01 - 2003-10-14; 30123572
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings - May 2006 - June 2007, 2006-02-01 - 2006-12-11; 30123576
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings - Fiscal Year [FY] 2003 - January - June 2003 - Education Sector Human Development Network - Volume 1, 2003-04-07 - 2003-06-18; 30123610
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings - Fiscal Year [FY] 2003 - January - June 2003 - Education Sector Human Development Network - Volume 2, 2002-12-16 - 2003-04-09; 30123611
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings - Fiscal Year [FY] 2002 - September - December 2002 - Education Sector Human Development Network, 2002-09-04 - 2002-11-21; 30123612
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] Sector Managers File - Chronological Record 2001 - August 2001, 2001-08-10 - 2002-01-16; 30123613
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the President [EXC] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2005, 2004-09-24 - 2005-12-01; 30123614
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2003, 2002-05-15 - 2003-11-10; 30123615
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2004, 2004-02-25 - 2004-11-17; 30123616
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2005, 2004-11-12 - 2005-09-28; 30123617
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the President [EXC] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2002 - Volume 1, 2002-02-06 - 2002-04-30; 30123618
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the President [EXC] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2002 - Volume 2, 2002-05-08 - 2002-12-26; 30123619
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the President [EXC] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2003, 2002-04-26 - 2003-10-28; 30123620
  - Education Group of the Human Development Network [HDNED] - Office of the President [EXC] External Correspondence [En-Corr] - 2004, 2004-01-15 - 2004-12-22; 30123621
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings Fiscal Year [FY] 2001 - July 2000 - June 2001 - Education Sector Human Development Network - Volume 1, 2000-01-20 - 2001-06-14; 30123622
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings Fiscal Year [FY] 2001 - July 2000 - June 2001 - Education Sector Human Development Network - Volume 2, 2000-05-25 - 2001-03-16; 30123623
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings Fiscal Year [FY] 2001 - July 2000 - June 2001 - Education Sector Human Development Network - Volume 3, 2000-05-25 - 2000-10-25; 30123624
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings - Fiscal Year [FY] 2002 - May - August 2002 - Education Sector Human Development Network - Volume 1, 2002-06-13 - 2002-07-18; 30123639
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings - Fiscal Year [FY] 2002 - May - August 2002 - Education Sector Human Development Network - Volume 2, 2002-05-07 - 2002-06-13; 30123640
  - Education Sector Board [ESB] Meetings - Fiscal Year [FY]2001 - Fiscal Year [FY] 2002 - July 2001 - April 2002 - Education Sector Human Development Network, 2001-06-29 - 2002-06-12; 30123641
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 1, 1996-12-01 - 1996-12-31; 01677544
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 2, 1997-01-01 - 1997-05-31; 01677545
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 3, 1996-11-01 - 1997-05-31; 01677546
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 4, 1997-03-01 - 1997-05-31; 01677547
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 5, 1997-02-01 - 1997-05-31; 01677548
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 6, 1997-01-01 - 1997-05-01; 01677549
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 7, 1996-12-01 - 1997-05-31; 01677550
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 8, 1997-03-01 - 1997-07-01; 01677551
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 9, 1997-06-01 - 1997-10-01; 01677552
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 10, 1997-08-01 - 1997-10-01; 01677553
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 11, 1997-05-01 - 1997-10-01; 01677554
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 12, 1997-09-01 - 1997-10-31; 01677555
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 13, 1997-08-01 - 1997-12-01; 01677556
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 14, 1997-02-01 - 1997-12-01; 01677557
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 15, 1997-08-01 - 1997-12-01; 01677558
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 16, 1997-12-01 - 1997-12-31; 01677559
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 17, 1998-01-01 - 1998-01-31; 01677560
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 18, 1998-02-01 - 1998-03-03; 01677561
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 19, 1998-03-01 - 1998-03-31; 01677562
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 20, 1997-12-01 - 1998-05-01; 01677563
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 21, 1998-05-01 - 1998-05-31; 01677635
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 22, 1998-05-01 - 1998-07-01; 01677636
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 23, 1998-06-01 - 1998-07-31; 01677637
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 24, 1996-07-01 - 1998-10-01; 01677638
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 25, 1996-07-01 - 1998-10-01; 01677639
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 26, 1997-11-01 - 1998-12-01; 01677640
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 27, 1998-12-01 - 1998-12-31; 01677641
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 28, 1998-01-01 - 1999-01-31; 01677642
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 29, 1999-02-01 - 1999-03-03; 01677643
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 30, 1997-03-01 - 1999-03-31; 01677644
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 31, 1999-04-01 - 1999-05-31; 01677645
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 32, 1999-05-01 - 1999-07-01; 01677646
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 33, 1999-06-01 - 1999-07-01; 01677647
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 34, 1999-06-01 - 1999-07-31; 01677648
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 35, 1998-07-01 - 1999-07-31; 01677649
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 36, 1999-08-01 - 1999-10-31; 01677650
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 37, 1999-10-01 - 1999-10-31; 01677651
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 38, 1999-11-01 - 1999-12-01; 01677652
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 39, 2000-01-01 - 2000-01-31; 01677653
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 40, 2000-01-01 - 2000-03-02; 01677654
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 41, 2000-02-01 - 2000-03-31; 01677655
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 42, 2000-03-01 - 2000-07-01; 01677656
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 43, 2000-03-01 - 2000-05-31; 01677657
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 44, 2000-06-01 - 2000-07-31; 01677658
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 45, 2000-06-01 - 2000-07-31; 01677659
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 46, 1999-01-01 - 2000-08-31; 01677660
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 47, 2000-08-01 - 2000-08-31; 01677661
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 48, 2000-09-01 - 2000-10-31; 01677662
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 49, 2000-09-01 - 2000-10-31; 01677663
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 50, 2000-10-01 - 2000-12-01; 01677664
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 51, 2000-12-01 - 2000-12-31; 01677665
  - Education Sector Board - Meetings - Correspondence 52, 2001-04-01 - 2001-05-01; 01677893
  - District of Columbia (D.C.) Community Outreach Program - Grants Committee Meeting - Correspondence 1, 1998-08-01 - 1998-10-01; 01677694
  - District of Columbia (D.C.) Community Outreach Program - Grants Committee Meeting - Correspondence 2, 1998-06-01 - 1999-10-01; 01677695
  - District of Columbia (D.C.) Community Outreach Program - Grants Committee Meeting - Correspondence 3, 1998-05-01 - 1998-12-31; 01677696
  - District of Columbia (D.C.) Community Outreach Program - Grants Committee Meeting - Correspondence 4, 1999-02-01 - 1999-05-01; 01677697
  - James D. Wolfensohn - Correspondence - Correspondence, 1996-06-01 - 1998-10-01; 01677743
  - HDD Front Office - Correspondence / Querries - Correspondence, 1996-04-01 - 1997-07-31; 01677752
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 1, 1995-10-01 - 1996-10-31; 01677859
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 2, 1996-07-01 - 1996-10-31; 01677860
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 3, 1997-01-01 - 1997-03-31; 01677861
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 4, 1996-10-01 - 1997-01-31; 01677862
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 5, 1997-03-01 - 1997-10-01; 01677863
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 6, 1997-03-01 - 1997-05-31; 01677864
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 7, 1997-06-01 - 1997-10-01; 01677865
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 8, 1997-06-01 - 1997-10-01; 01677866
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 9, 1997-02-01 - 1998-05-31; 01677867
  - Education Sector Board (ESB) - Chronological Files - Correspondence 10, 2000-01-01 - 2000-05-31; 01677890
  - Exc Executive Director (ED's) Offices - Correspondence, 1996-06-01 - 1997-05-01; 01677899
  - Human Development (HD) Network - Education - Correspondence, 1996-09-01 - 1996-12-31; 01677900
  - Human Development (HD) Network - Education / Communications - Correspondence, 1996-08-01 - 1997-05-01; 01677926
  - Human Development (HD) Network - Education / Knowledge Management - Correspondence, 1996-08-01 - 1997-10-01; 01677928
  - Human Development (HD) Network - Education / Quality - Correspondence, 1996-08-01 - 1997-03-31; 01677930
  - Human Development (HD) Network - Personnel - Correspondence, 1996-10-01 - 1997-03-31; 01677941
  - Human Development (HD) Network - Council - Correspondence 1, 1996-08-01 - 1997-05-31; 01677943
  - Human Development (HD) Network - Council - Correspondence 2, 1996-06-01 - 1996-08-31; 01677944
  - Human Development (HD) Networks - General - Correspondence, 1996-08-01 - 1997-07-31; 01677960
  - Topics - African American Institute - Correspondence, 1997-08-01 - 1997-10-01; 01677962
  - Topics - The British Council - Correspondence, 1996-02-01 - 1997-05-31; 01677963
  - Topics - Budget - Correspondence, 1996-06-01 - 1996-07-01; 01677965
  - Topics - District of Columbia (D.C.) Initiative - Correspondence, 1997-07-01 - 1997-07-31; 01677967
  - Topics - Distance Education - Correspondence, 1997-07-01 - 1997-07-31; 01677968
  - Topics - Educational Testing Service - Correspondence, 1995-10-01 - 1997-07-31; 01677969
  - Topics - External Requests for Funding - Correspondence, 1997-08-01 - 1997-08-31; 01677977
  - Topics - Forum for African Women Educationalists - Correspondence, 1997-08-01 - 1997-08-31; 01677978
  - Topics - Microsoft - Meeting - Correspondence, 1997-06-01 - 1997-07-31; 01678006
  - Topics - Outsourcing Policy - Correspondence, 1997-06-01 - 1997-07-01; 01678007
  - Topics - Pacific Pathways Consultants - Correspondence, 1995-06-01 - 1997-03-03; 01678008
  - Topics - Soros Foundation - Correspondence, 1997-07-01 - 1997-10-31; 01678009
  - Topics - Strategic Compact - Correspondence, 1997-02-01 - 1997-08-31; 01678010
  - Topics - Strategy - Correspondence 1, 1997-05-01 - 1997-07-01; 01678012
  - Topics - Strategy - Correspondence 2, 1997-05-01 - 1997-07-01; 01678013
  - Topics - Task Force on Higher Education - Correspondence, 1997-08-01 - 1997-08-31; 01678034